Register of the Poland. Poselstwo (Belgium) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Poselstwo (Belgium) records,
1933-1940
59034
Poland. Poselstwo (Belgium)
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, telegrams, and dispatches, relating to Polish-Belgian relations and to Polish diplomacy during World War II. A digital copy of this entire collection is available at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/43/0/-/.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
Also available on microfilm (1 reel).
Digital copy in Poland's National Digital Archive at http://szukajwarchiwach.pl/800/43/0/-/. It was digitized from microfilm by the Polish State Archives.
Historical Note
Polish legation in Belgium.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists mainly of the secret correspondence sent and received by the Polish legation in Belgium between the early 1930s and the first few months of World War II, relating to Polish-Belgian relations during the interwar period and to Polish diplomacy at the outbreak of the war. Also included are lists and instructions regarding the code system, which was frequently broken by the Germans.
These records were formerly part of the Polish Foreign Ministry collection, acquired by the Hoover Archives in 1959, and were accessioned in the early 1990s as a separate collection.
A microfilm copy of these materials has been deposited in the State Archives of Poland in Warsaw.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Belgium--Foreign relations--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945.; Poland.; Belgium.; Poland--Foreign relations--Belgium.
Series Description
- Decoded Letters, 1936-1939. (Box 1)
  Logbook of incoming and outgoing correspondence
- Decoded Telegrams, 1933-1940. (Box 1)
  Incoming and outgoing telegrams, as well as instructions relating to the code, arranged chronologically. Includes lists
Container List
- DECODED LETTERS, 1936-1939. (Box-folder 1: 1)
  Logbook of incoming (1936 February 24 - 1939 November 2) and outgoing (1936 February 21 - 1939 August 10) letters
- DECODED TELEGRAMS, 1933-1940.
  Incoming and outgoing telegrams, and instructions relating to the code
  - General
    - General. List (Folder 1: 2)
    - 1935 (Folder 1: 3)
    - 1936 (Folder 1: 4)
    - 1937 (Folder 1: 5)
    - 1938 (Folder 1: 6)
    - 1939 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Instructions
    - General. List (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1933 (Folder 1: 9)
    - 1934 (Folder 1: 10)
    - 1935 (Folder 1: 11)
    - 1939 (Folder 1: 12)
    - 1940 (Folder 1: 13)